Boyars mss., 1960-2010 LMC 2953
Lilly Library
Boyars mss.
1960-2009
Lilly Library
Marion Boyars Publishing Ltd.
Boyars, Marion Ursula (Asmus), 1927-1999
LMC 2953
74 Boxes
The Boyars mss., 1960-2010, consist of the publication materials, correspondence, professional records, and financial files of Marion Boyars Publishing Ltd, as well as a small amount of personal material belonging to Marion Boyars.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchase: 2012
Biographical Note
Born on October 26, 1927 to German publisher Johannes Asmus, Marion Boyars spent her childhood in New York and Switzerland, going on to earn a degree in politics, philosophy, and economics from Keele University at a time when few women attended British universities (McNamara, 1997). Boyars (then Marion Asmus) married clothing manufacturer George Lobbenberg and had two daughters, Susan and Catheryn. Through an ad in The Bookseller shown to her by her financial advisor in 1960, Boyars bought a 50% stake – allegedly funded by the alimony of her divorce from Lobbenberg – in independent publisher John Calder's firm Calder Publishers. Boyars claims that her interest in publishing was due to a desire for "a career that was intellectually stimulating and demanding" as well as to "give voice to exciting new ideas" (McNamara, 1997). It was through this firm, which became Calder and Boyars Ltd. in 1964, that she met her second husband, translator and poet Arthur Boyars. The firm specialized in translated fiction, the writings of modern composers, social sciences, film studies, and controversial literature, notably including the works of Hubert Selby Jr. and Henry Miller. Due to insurmountable differences, Calder and Boyars began to dissolve the firm in 1975, dividing their published authors between them over the next five years while forming Calder Publishers and Marion Boyars Publishers, respectively.
As "the first woman in the United Kingdom to become a publisher in her own right – not through marriage or inheritance" as well as the "first woman British publisher to establish an American firm" (Reuter, 1978), Boyars continued to favor experimental fiction and politically radical non-fiction as Marion Boyars Publishers. According to Boyars, she "mainly broke the rules because she didn't know them" (McNamara, 1997), though she also firmly believed that obscenity and taboos were "necessary subjects" (McNamara, 1997). Though other publishers and authors' agents found her to be "slightly eccentric, publishing books no one else wants" (McNamara, 1997), they also noted her success at selecting and promoting authors and their works, often trying to steal authors from Boyars after she had discovered them. With roughly 20-25 books published annually, Marion Boyars Publishers published six authors who went on to win Nobel Prizes and was often the first publisher to bring international authors to English audiences. Boyars's conviction regarding the importance of publishing avant-garde and challenging subject matter also led her to publish a not-insignificant number of queer authors and stories; in 1976, Boyars was involved in challenging the obscenity and blasphemy charges of James Kirkup's poem "The Love that Dares to Speak its Name" as well as the magazine in which it was published, Gay Times. After Boyars's death in 1999, her daughter Catheryn Kilgariff continued to run the firm.
Cited Sources
Reuter, Madalynne. (1978, October 2). "London publisher launches U.S. firm.". The Publishers weekly (0000-0019), 214, p. 38.
McNamara, Katherine. (1997). "Institutional Memory: A Conversation with Marion Boyars." Archipelago, Vol. 1 No. 3: http://www.archipelago.org/vol1-3/boyers1.htm
Scope and Contents
Publishing Files consist of cover proofs, galleys, correspondence, drafts, and all other materials related to the publication of texts at Marion Boyars Publishing Ltd. Correspondence includes letters to and from Boyars arranged by author, though the author is sometimes the subject rather than the sender or recipient. Professional Files consist of various subject files related to marketing and promotion as well as Boyars's involvement in the publishing field as a whole. Financial includes ledger books, ledger cards, and royalty statements.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following series: Publishing Files, Correspondence, Professional Files, Financial, Personal, and Miscellaneous. Materials are arranged alphabetically when possible. While there is overlap between the Publishing Files and Correspondence series, the archivist chose to sort materials according to the folders and systems in which they arrived in order to preserve the record organization employed by the publishing firm itself.
Related Materials
See Calder & Boyars mss., Kael mss., and Red Dust mss., also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
- Publishing Files
  - Ableman, Paul
    - Photographs, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The Secret of Consciousness - reviews, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Secret of Consciousness - correspondence and files, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The Secret of Consciousness - cover proofs, undated (Box 73 (oversize))
  - Abrahams, Gerald
    - Author file, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Agee, James
    - The Collected Poems of James Agee - cover proofs, undated (Box 74 (oversize))
  - Akhmadulina, Bella
    - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - The Garden - reviews, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Almansi, Guido
    - Author file, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Anders, Jill
    - McDaid's Wife - reviews, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - McDaid's Wife - cover mock-ups, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Andrews, Lyman
    - Kaleidoscope - reviews, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Kaleidoscope - cover proofs, undated (Box 74 (oversize))
  - Aries, Philippe
    - Author file, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Western Attitudes Towards Death - correspondence and files, 1975-1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Western Attitudes Towards Death - cover proofs, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Atkins, Meg Elizabeth
    - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - The Folly - reviews, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Tangle - reviews, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Tangle - correspondence and files, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - The Folly - cover proofs, undated (Box 72 (oversize))
  - Aubrey, Crispin
    - Nukespeak - reviews, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Babbitz, Eve
    - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Barber, Dulan
    - A World Without Wool Shops - reviews, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - A World Without Wool Shops - cover proofs, correspondence and files, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Barnes, Rosy
    - Sadomasochism for Accountants - cover proofs, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Sadomasochism for Accountants - reviews, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bataille, Georges
    - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - My Mother, Madame Edwarda, The Dead Man - correspondence and files, 1989-2004 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
    - My Mother, Madame Edwarda, The Dead Man - correspondence and files of translator Austryn Wainhouse, 1969-1988 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - My Mother, Madame Edwarda, The Dead Man - cover proofs, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - My Mother, Madame Edwarda, The Dead Man - reviews, 1989-2001 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Blue of Noon - cover proofs, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Blue of Noon - correspondence and files, 1979-1999 (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
    - The Story of the Eye - correspondence and files, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
    - Literature and Evil - reviews, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Literature and Evil - cover proofs, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Literature and Evil - correspondence and files, 1983-2006 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Eroticism - correspondence and files, 1986-1993 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Eroticism - reviews, 1994-1999 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Eroticism - cover proofs, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - L'Abbe C - cover drafts, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - L'Abbe C - cover proofs, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - L'Abbe C - correspondence and files, 1983-1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - L'Abbe C - cover proofs, undated (Box 70 (oversize))
    - General reviews, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Beirne, Gerard
    - The Eskimo in the Net - reviews, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Four Stories - draft, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Author file, 2003-2004 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Bellocchio, Marco
    - China is Near - cover proofs, undated (Box 69 (oversize))
  - Beresford, Anne
    - Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bergman, Ingmar
    - Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Author file, 1976? (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Four Stories - correspondence and files, 1977-1983 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Four Stories - cover proofs, undated (Box 72 (oversize))
    - A Film Trilogy - correspondence and files, 1967-1988 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
    - A Film Trilogy - cover proofs, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - A Film Trilogy - reviews, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Scenes from a Marriage - cover drafts and proofs, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Scenes from a Marriage - reviews, 1975-1990 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - The Serpent's Egg - correspondence and files, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - The Serpent's Egg - cover proofs, undated (Box 73 (oversize))
    - Persona and Shame - cover proofs, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Persona and Shame - cover proofs, undated (Box 73 (oversize))
    - Face to Face - correspondence and files, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Face to Face - cover proofs, undated (Box 69 (oversize))
    - Stills, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Berio, Luciano
    - Two Interviews - reviews, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Two Interviews - cover proofs, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Two Interviews - cover proofs, undated (Box 70 (oversize))
  - Bernard, Jessie
    - The Future of Parenthood - reviews, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - The Future of Parenthood - cover proofs, undated (Box 72 (oversize))
  - Bersani, Leo
    - A Future for Astyanax - reviews, correspondence and files, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - A Future for Astyanax - cover proofs, undated (Box 72 (oversize))
    - Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Bichsel, Peter
    - Stories for Children - cover proofs, correspondence and files, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Bills, Greg
    - Consider This Home - reviews, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Consider This Home - correspondence and files, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Blackbridge, Persimmon
    - Prozac Highway - cover proofs, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Prozac Highway - page proofs, undated (Box 2, Folder 32-33)
    - Prozac Highway - reviews, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Bleys, Olivier
    - Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Bobrowski, Johannes
    - Levin's Mill - reviews, 1988-1996 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Levin's Mill - correspondence and files, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Levin's Mill - cover drafts and proofs, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Levin's Mill - cover proofs, undated (Box 74 (oversize))
  - von Bohlen, Claude
    - Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Bohm, Karl
    - Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - A Life Remembered - photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - A Life Remembered - xerox (German), undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - A Life Remembered - reviews, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - A Life Remembered - correspondence and files, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - A Life Remembered - cover proofs, undated (Box 74 (oversize))
  - Boland, Eavan
    - Photographs, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Author file, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Boll, Heinrich
    - Reviews, 1995-2008 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Absent Without Leave - reviews, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Absent Without Leave - correspondence and files, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Absent Without Leave - cover proofs, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - The Clown - cover proofs, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - The Clown - reviews, 1987-1995 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - The Clown - cover proofs, undated (Box 69 (oversize))
    - Billiards at Half Past Nine - cover proofs, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Borchert, Wolfgang
    - The Man Outside - cover drafts, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - The Man Outside - cover proofs, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - The Man Outside - correspondence and files, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - The Man Outside - reviews, 1992-1998 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - The Sad Geraniums - reviews, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Bree, Germaine
    - Camus & Sartre - reviews, 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Camus & Sartre - cover proofs, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Camus & Sartre - cover proofs, undated (Box 71 (oversize))
  - Brenot, Philippe
    - In Praise of Masturbation - cover proofs, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - In Praise of Masturbation - review, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Brisac, Genevieve
    - Photographs, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Losing Eugenio - cover proofs, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Losing Eugenio - reviews, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Looking for Eugenio - reviews, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Broderick, John
    - Photographs, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - The Rose Tree - reviews, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - The Rose Tree - correspondence and files, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - The Rose Tree - cover proofs, undated (Box 73 (oversize))
    - The Flood - correspondence and files, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - The Flood - reviews, 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - The Flood - cover proofs, undated (Box 72 (oversize))
    - A Prayer for Fair Weather - reviews, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - A Prayer for Fair Weather - cover proofs, undated (Box 73 (oversize))
    - The Trial of Father Dillingham - reviews, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - The Trial of Father Dillingham - correspondence and files, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - The Trial of Father Dillingham - cover drafts and proofs, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - The Irish Magdalen - cover proofs, undated (Box 74 (oversize))
    - Author file, 1986-2004 (Box 40, Folder 2-4)
  - Brokken, Jan
    - Photographs, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Jungle Rudy - cover proofs, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Jungle Rudy - reviews, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Brook, Rhidian
    - More Than Eyes Can See - cover proofs, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - More Than Eyes Can See - reviews, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Bryher, Winifred
    - The Days of Mars - reviews, 1972-1981 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - The Days of Mars - cover proofs, correspondence and files, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - The Days of Mars - page proofs, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Bucklow, Spike
    - The Alchemy of Paint - reviews, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Bullock, Michael
    - Randolph Cranstone and the Glass Thimble - typescript, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Randolph Cranstone and the Glass Thimble - correspondence and files, 1975-1978 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Randolph Cranstone and the Glass Thimble - draft, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Last Message Through Rain - draft, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Author file, 1976-1980 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Bunuel, Jeanne
    - A Woman Without a Piano - draft, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Burford, E. J.
    - The Orrible Synne - correspondence and files, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - The Orrible Synne - reviews, 1973-1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Burman, Carina
    - The Streets of Babylon - interview with translator Sarah Death, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - The Streets of Babylon - reviews, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Burns, Alan
    - Dreamerika - cover layout, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Europe After the Rain - cover proofs, undated (Box 69 (oversize))
  - Burrows, Tim
    - From CBGB to the Roundhouse - reviews, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - From CBGB to the Roundhouse - cover proofs, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Busch, Frederick
    - Breathing Trouble - reviews, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Breathing Trouble - cover proofs, undated (Box 70 (oversize))
    - Photographs, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Buss, Robin
    - French Film Noir - cover layout and page proofs, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - French Film Noir - cover proofs, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - French Film Noir - correspondence and files, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - French Film Noir - reviews, 1994-2001 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - French Film Noir - photographs, undated (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - French Film Noir - cover proofs, undated (Box 72 (oversize))
    - Taking a Second Look - drafts and files, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes floppy discs (2)
    - Taking a Second Look - typescript, 1999? (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
  - Butti, Ken
    - A Golden Thread - correspondence and files, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Cadman, Eileen; Gail Chester & Agnes Pivot
    - Rolling Our Own - reviews, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Cage, John
    - Author file, 1977-1998 (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
    - For the Birds - typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - For the Birds - cover draft, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - For the Birds - correspondence and files, 1981-1995 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - M - reviews, 1973-1998 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - M - correspondence and files, 1976-1998 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - A Year from Monday - correspondence and files, 1975-1985 (Box 4, Folder 28-29)
    - X - correspondence and files, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - X - cover drafts, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - X - reviews, 1985-1990 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Empty Words - correspondence and files, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Calisher, Hortense
    - Age - corresondence and files, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Age - reviews, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - In the Slammer with Carol Smith - reviews, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - In the Slammer with Carol Smith - cover proofs, undated (Box 74 (oversize))
    - Photographs, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Callaghan, Mary Rose
    - Photographs, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - I Met A Man Who Wasn't There - reviews, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Confessions of a Prodigal Daughter - reviews, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Confessions of a Prodigal Daughter - correpsondence and files, 1985-1987 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Confessions of a Prodigal Daughter - cover proofs, undated (Box 69 (oversize))
  - Canetti, Elias
    - The Numbered - correspondence and files, 1983-1986 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - The Numbered - cover proofs, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - The Numbered - reviews, 1982-1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - The Numbered - cover proofs, undated (Box 74 (oversize))
    - Kafka's Other Trial - reviews, 1975-1994 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Kafka's Other Trial - correspondence and files, 1976-1988 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Kafka's Other Trial - cover proofs, undated (Box 74 (oversize))
    - Author file, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Reviews and publicity, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - The Voices of Marrakesh - reviews, 1999-2008 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - The Voices of Marrakesh - typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - The Voices of Marrakesh - cover proofs, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Caplan, Jonathan
    - Author file, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Carnie, Jamie
    - Blue Sky Thoughts - reviews, 2007-2008 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Cator, Victoria and Lucinda Bruce
    - Victoria and Lucinda's Flavour of the Month - reviews, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Charters, Samuel
    - Louisiana Black - correspondence and files, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Louisiana Black - reviews, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Louisiana Black - page proofs, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - The Day is so Long and the Wages so Small - correspondence and files, 2002-2003 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - The Day is so Long and the Wages so Small - reviews, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - The Day is so Long and the Wages so Small - typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - The Day is so Long and the Wages so Small - cover proofs, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - New Orleans: Playing a Jazz Chorus - reviews, 2007-2008 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Mr. Jabi & Mr. Smythe - reviews, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Jelly Roll Morton's Last Night at the Jungle Inn - reviews, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Jelly Roll Morton's Last Night at the Jungle Inn - cover proofs, undated (Box 74 (oversize))
    - Roots of the Blues - correspondence and files, 1980-1992 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Roots of the Blues - reviews, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Roots of the Blues - cover proofs, undated (Box 70 (oversize))
    - Legacy of the Blues - correspondence and files, 1997? (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Legacy of the Blues - reviews, 1992-1998 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Legacy of the Blues - cover proofs, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Legacy of the Blues - cover proofs, undated (Box 74 (oversize))
  - Chilton, Paul & Crispin Aubrey
    - 1984 in 1984 - files, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Claesson, Bent H.
    - Boy Girl Man Woman - cover proofs, undated (Box 71 (oversize))
  - Clark, Clara
    - Coping Alone - review, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Cocteau, Jean
    - Two Screenplays - cover drafts, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Two Screenplays - cover proofs, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Two Screenplays - correspondence and files, 1975-1989 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Two Screenplays - reviews, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - The Art of Cinema - cover proofs, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - The Art of Cinema - cover proofs, undated (Box 70 (oversize))
  - Cohen, Nicholas
    - Photographs, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Author file, 1975-1980 (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
  - Coleman, Earl
    - "B. Ross, Artist, Shot", 1994 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Collins, Clive
    - Sachiko's Wedding - correspondence and files, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Sachiko's Wedding - page proofs, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Sachiko's Wedding - corrected page proofs, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - The Blue Horizon - typescript, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
    - The Foreign Husband - correspondence and files, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - The Foreign Husband - reviews, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - The Foreign Husband - cover drafts, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - The Foreign Husband - cover proofs, undated (Box 72 (oversize))
    - Work - typescript, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 13-15)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Author file, 1991-1993 (Box 6, Folder 17-19)
  - Collins, Peter
    - Ideology After the Fall of Communism - correspondence and files, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Collins, Warwick
    - Computer One - correspondence and files, 1997? (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Computer One - reviews, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Computer One - cover proofs, undated (Box 69 (oversize))
    - Gents - reviews, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Gents (screenplay) - typescript, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Gents (novel) - typescript, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Gents (novel) - cover proofs, undated (Box 72 (oversize))
    - Evolution - typescript, 1994-1996 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Fuckwoman (novel) - typescript, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Fuckwoman (screenplay) - typescript, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - The Rationalist (screenplay) - typescript, 1995? (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - An Elderly Satyr - typescript (Vol. I), 1998 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - An Elderly Satyr - typescript (Vol. II), 1998 (Box 7, Folder 8)